Ashish Sheelavantar

+91-9886006107 <u>pluckyashish@gmail.com</u> <u>https://github.com/msashish</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashish-sheelavantar-79241662/

Profile

I am a passionate technology professional with Engineering team lead experience. I've a wide range hands-on experience in developing Cloud (GCP) applications, Big Data applications, Web applications, Data pipelines, Utility applications for Banking and Financial domain. I use AI to be efficient and have created utility Apps.

Skills

Languages: React.js, Python, Java

GCP: GKE, DataFlow, BigQuery, Pub/Sub, Cloud Functions, CloudBuild

Frameworks: Flask/Django/FastAPI, Celery, Graphql, SpringBoot

Hadoop: Spark, HBASE, Oozie

CI CD: Docker, Terraform, CodeFresh, Github Actions, CloudBuild, Jenkins

Al: LangChain, LLMs (Gemini, OpenAl, Claude Sonnet), CoPilot Others: Kafka, Kubernetes/OpenShift, MongoDB, Redis, Postgresql

Experience

LEAD CLOUD ENGINEER; ANZ TECHNOLOGIES; 2023-CURRENT

I lead technical development for components of Federated data mesh on GCP.

Core data mesh components:

Designed and co-developed Mesh portal, Catalog service using GKE, VPC, IAM, Postgresql, BigQuery, Kafka, Pubsub, Terraform, CloudBuild, CloudFunctions. Frontend was developed using React.js & backend using Python FastAPI. I recently added comments UI feature using React.js.

Integration components for mesh:

- Designed and built DLP wrapper for BYOD customers & data quality publisher for data mesh using Cloud Functions & pubsub
- Built Terraform modules for Data Node capabilities (CloudBuild, IAM, VPC-SC)
- As part of Hackathon, built Al matching utility App using LangChain & LLMs

Data Engineering on Cloud:

 I co-designed and developed batch & streaming ingestion pipelines between onprem and GCP as well as within GCP using Composer, DataFlow, CloudFunctions, BigQuery. 2) I've setup CICD pipelines using CloudBuild, Terraform. Includes utility scripts, VPC-SC setup, multiple docker images. As part of SRE, I setup SLO, SLA and alert policies along with dashboards in Grafana.

LEAD HADOOP WEB DEVELOPER; ANZ TECHNOLOGIES; 2021-2022

This is a full stack App with components hosted on Cloudera Hadoop and Openshift k8.

- Spark, Oozie, Hbase, Hive for data processing
- React.js for Frontend SPA and Java Springboot for backend services

FULLSTACK ENGINEER; ANZ TECHNOLOGIES - 2019-2020

We specialised in building multiple Utility Applications for businesses across ANZ. Tech stack used: React.js, Python, Docker, Oracle, OpenShift, RobotFramework

- We developed Metadata Webapp as a central App to store all data platform's metadata. I developed frontend (react.js) and backend components (python fastapi) hosted on K8 OpenShift for managing Interface agreements
- We developed a batch Data Ingestion Framework for on-prem using Python
- We automated testing suite called Xpression & reduced effort from 16 hours to ~30 minutes. This involved writing Python wrappers to interact with MS email, SharePoint

SR HADOOP DATA ENGINEER; ANZ TECHNOLOGIES - 2016-2018

I worked on Big Data platform on multiple applications. Tech stack used: Tech Stack: antlr, Hadoop, Hive, Spark, Python, Docker, Oracle, SQLite, Flask, Bamboo, Java, Spring Boot, Oozie

- Developed metadata driven CD application using Java Spring Boot
- Designed and Developed pyspark based Data Curation process on Hadoop (SCD2, standardise, stitch/filter/dedupe)

SOLUTION DESIGNER; ANZ TECHNOLOGIES – 2013-2015

I was mainly involved in End to end Data Modelling for APRA, MAS Regulatory data;

TECHNICAL LEAD; INFOSYS TECHNOLOGIES – 2003-2012

I started as Mainframes Developer with COBOL, DB2 stored procedures and worked on **Amex** Credit Card loyalty applications (Rebates and CoBrand)

Education & Certifications

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics & Communications

GCP Professional Data Engineer AWS Practitioner TOGAF 9.1